Hello everyone, I am Kaichao
大家好 我是凯超
The content of this lesson includes
本次课程内容是
generic types, traits and lifetimes in Rust
Rust的泛型, trait和生命周期
First we will introduce the concept of generic types
首先我们会介绍一下泛型的概念
then how to use trait
接着是如何使用trait
and the lifetime of variables and references
以及变量和引用的生命周期的使用
So why use generic types?
那为什么要使用泛型呢
In previous lessons we have mentioned that
我们之前的课程讲到过
we can encapsulate modular code for code reuse
可以通过模块化的代码封装
实现代码的复用
For common used modules
一些公共的模块
we can provide some interfaces
我们可以开放一些接口
so that it can be used by other code
供其他的代码所使用
There is a another way to reuse the shared code
还有另外一种形式的代码复用机制
through generic types
就是通过泛型
When data structures or functions are similar
当一些数据结构或者函数的功能
很类似时
we can use generic types
可以使用泛型
We'll look at some examples later
后面我们会看一些例子
By abstracting with generic types
通过泛型这种抽象
we can increase the extensibility of the code
我们可以增加代码的可扩展性
When adding a new data structure
当我们新增了一个数据结构的时候
we don't need to change the existing function
我们不需要改变已有的函数
because
因为
the current function may accept a parameter of generic type
当前的函数可能是接受一个泛型参数
Then our new data structure only need to meet the constraints of this generic type
那我们新增的这个数据结构
只要满足这个泛型参数所对应的约束就可以了
Then our new data structure only need to meet the constraints of this generic type
Generic types are often used in the definition of struct, enum and function signature
泛型常用于结构体的定义, 枚举定义和函数签名
Now let's look at an example of struct
现在我们来看一个结构体的例子
Here we define a struct called Point
这里我们定义了一个表示
it represents a point on the coordinate system
坐标系上的一个点的结构体Point
It has two attributes which are x, y
它有两个属性分别是x y
here x, y can be an integer or float
那x y可以是整数 也可以是浮点数
Now we can use generic type to reduce the definition of similar structs
这个时候我们就可以
通过泛型来减少类似的结构体定义
Now we can use generic type to reduce the definition of similar structs
here we use an angle bracket
那我们是通过一个尖括号
it contains a generic type T
里面包含一个泛型的参数T
by convention we capitalize the letter to represent the generic type
约定俗成的 我们以大写的单字母来表示我们的泛型
If it has only one generic type
如果是一个泛型参数的话
we usually use T
我们通常使用T
it is the first letter (T) of type
也就是type的首字母T
Here we implement a function x for our struct
这里我们为我们的结构体实现了一个方法x
Its parameter is a reference to the struct itself
它的参数是结构体自身的一个引用
then returns a reference to T
那返回一个T的引用
Note that
这里要注意我们在
when implementing the corresponding struct
实现对应的结构体的时候
after the keyword impl, we need to add the generic type T
我们在implement后面要加一个
在implement后面要指定我们的泛型T
we also need to indicate it here if there are constraints to the generic type
如果有泛型约束的话 我们也要添加在对应的后面
The logic of the x method here is very simple
这里x方法的逻辑很简单就是获取
it gets the field x of the struct
当前结构体的x
and returns a reference to x
属性并且返回它的引用
Let's look at the main function
可以看到
当我们在main函数里面可以定义
we can define a point where x and y are integer
x y分别是整数的这样的一个point结构体
we can also define a point where x and y are float number
也可以定义x y是浮点数对应的结构体float
Let's look at another example for enum
我们再来看一个枚举的例子
In the previous lesson we mentioned that
我们之前课程中讲到过
there are two important enums
两个重要的枚举
One is Option, represents containing a value or None
一个是Option 表示有值或者无值
If containing a value
那有值的话
the type of the value can be integer, float, string etc.
这个值的类型我们可以是整数, 可以是浮点数, 可以字符串, 等等
Here we can use generic type T for abstraction
那我们这里就可以用一个泛型T进行抽象
it makes our code more extensible and flexible
让我们的代码可扩展性更强也更灵活
Similarly, for the Result enum
那同样的我们的Result类型
it has two generic types, T and E
它有两个泛型参数
separated by comma
通过逗号进行分割
the first generic type parameter T represents the type of a value in correct cases
第一个泛型参数表示正确的情况下 值的类型
The second parameter E represents the type of error information in error cases
那第二个参数E 表示错误场景下的错误类型
Now let's look at an example
现在我们来看一个
that generic type is used in function signatures
泛型参数用在函数签名里的例子
Here we define a function largest
这里我们定义了一个函数largest
It takes a parameter called list
它接收一个参数list
its type is a reference to a vector
它的类型是集合类型的引用
the logic is pretty simple
它的逻辑很简单
It will get the maximum value in the vector
就是取得当前集合里面的最大值
and returns a reference of the value
并且返回该值的引用
Such a function can be used to calculate the maximum value of a vector of integers
这样一个函数可以去计算整数集合的最大值
or a vector of characters
也可以去计算字符集合的最大值
as long as the type inside the vector can be compared with each other
只要是里面的类型是可以比较大小的
then our function should be able to apply to such vectors
那我们这个函数都可以来应用
and calculate the maximum value in it
计算对应集合里面的最大值
Now let's look at the code
现在我们来看一下代码演示
First let's define the function largest
首先我们定义了函数largest
函数largest
the parameter is a reference to a vector
它的参数我们刚才提到了
它是某个集合类型的引用
returns a reference to an element in the vector
返回一个集合里面元素的引用
First it takes the first element of the input vector
首先我们取当前集合第一个元素
assign it to a mutable variable called largest
赋值给一个可变变量largest
Then it loops through each element in the vector
接着我们循环集合里面的每一个元素
compares the current element with the largest variable
将循环当前的元素与我们保存的临时
最大变量largest进行比较
If the current element is larger than the largest
如果是当前元素大于largest的话
we will update the largest to be the current element
我们将largest更新
When finishing the loop, the largest is returned
循环完成之后我们将largest返回
Then in the main function
我们在main函数里面
we define a vector of integers called number_list
紧接着我们在main函数里面
定义了一个整数集合 number_list
we define a vector of integers called number_list
then call the function largest and passes in a reference to the vector
我们调用largest函数 传入我们整数集合的引用
gets the result
然后返回结果
print it
将结果进行打印
Let's take a look at the result
我们来看一下打印的结果
We can see there is a compilation error here
可以看到我们这里有一个编译错误
that's because inside our largest function
那是因为我们的largest函数里面
we need to compare elements in the vector
需要进行比较大小
so the generic type T needs to have the capability to compare with each other
那我们的泛型参数T应该有一个比较大小的功能
Here we can use trait bound for the constraints
我们可以通过trait bound来进行对应的约束
The compiler alreadly reminds us
这里边已经给了我们提示
we need a constraint called PartialOrd
我们需要PartialOrd这样的一个约束
Details of trait bound will be introduced in the following content.
具体trait bound内容
我们会在后面的课程进行介绍
recompile
然后我们重新编译
At this time, our results have been printed correctly
可以看到
这时候我们的结果已经正常打印
the max value is 100
它最大值是100, 没有问题
Similarly, we can also compare a vector of characters
类似的我们还可以去比较一个
字符集合的大小
Similarly, we can also compare a vector of characters
to get the max character in it
来取得字符集合的最大值
Here let's define a vector of characters called char_list
这里我们定义了一个字符集合char_list
then call the function largest
然后我们调用largest这个函数
pass in a reference to the vector
传入这个集合
get the result and print it
获取结果并且打印
You can see our largest character is y
可以看到我们最大的char的话
应该是一个y
Let's take a look at the results of the execution
我们来看一下执行的结果
the result is expected
可以看到我们的执行结果也是正确的
Through this example you can see
那通过这个例子的话
大家就可以明显的看到
how we use generic types to reduce duplicated code and reuse the logic
我们通过使用泛型可以减少我们的代码
实现我们代码复用
There are several tips when using generic types
在使用泛型时有几个注意的点
The first is abount benefit
第一个是使用泛型的好处
using generic types in Rust will not affect the efficiency of code execution
Rust泛型
并不会影响代码的执行效率
This is because generic types are replaced by the concrete type at compile
这是因为泛型会在编译器编译期间替换为具体的类型
Another tip worth noting is that
另外一个需要注意的是
when your code has a lot of generic types, it will reduce the readability of the code
当你的代码里有非常多的泛型
那代码的可读性会降低
When you have a function with many generic types in the signature
当你某个函数的签名里面
有很多泛型的时候
This usually means that your code needs to be refactored
这说明你的代码
需要进行一个合理的重构
Next, let's take a look at trait in Rust
接着我们来看一下Rust里面的traits
A trait abstracts a certain capability or behavior
一个trait抽象了某种功能或者行为
it tells the compiler that some type can implement such capabilities
它告诉编译器这个类型
可以实现这样的功能
Different types can have same capabilities by implementing the same trait
那不同的类型都可以去具有这种行为
或者功能
For example, the capability to calculate the area
比如说计算面积的功能
a square can calculate its area, so does triangle
正方形可以有 三角形也可以有
Such a concept in Java is defined with interface
在Java里面这样的一个概念是通过
接口interface来实现的
Here let's look at the definition of trait
这里我们来看一下trait定义
We defined a trait named Summary
我们定义了一个trait 名字叫Summary
we use the pub keyword to make it visible to others
可以看到我们使用pub关键字来对外可见
In the case of trait Summary, there is a method called summarize
那summary的话有一个方法是summarize
it does not have a default implementation
它没有一个默认的实现
That is to say, the type that implement the summary trait must implement the method summarize
也就是说实现Summary trait的类型
必须要实现summarize这样的方法
Another scenario is
另外一种情况是
we defined a trait named Summary
同样的我们定义了Summary这样一个trait
but we give a default implementation to the summarize method
但是我们给
summarize这个函数定义了一个默认实现
For the type that implements the Summary trait
那实现Summary trait的类型
if such type want to use the default implementation
如果这样的类型是希望使用默认实现的话
then it doesn't need to implement the summarize method by itself
那他就不需要去实现summarize这个方法
We can combine generic types and traits together
我们可以把泛型和trait结合起来
the the generic can have some constraints
从而让泛型有了某种约束
that is to say
也就是说
only generics that satisfy these constraints can be used
满足这些约束的类型才可以使用
而不是接受任意的类型
rather than accepting any concrete type
In other words
换句话说就是
when the compiler tries to replace the generic type with a concrete type
当编译器尝试去替换泛型时
the concrete type must have the capability defined by this trait
这个具体的类型必须有
这个trait定义的功能或者行为
more specifically, the concrete type implements this trait
也就是说
这个具体类型实现了这个trait
Here let's look at an example
这里我们来看一个例子
It defines a struct called Tweet
我们定义的一个结构体是Tweet
which has two attributes, one is author and the other is text
它有两个属性 一个是author 一个是text
both are string type
它都是string类型
Let's implement the Summary trait we defined earlier for Tweet
那我们对Tweet
实现了我们之前定义的summary
Let's implement the Summary trait we defined earlier for Tweet
这样的一个接口
To implement the summarize function, we combine the content of author and text
那对应的summarize方法的实现
就是将两个
To implement the summarize function, we combine the content of author and text
将Tweet里面两个属性的内容进行拼接
return a string
返回一个string
Then we define another function called notify
我们又定义了一个函数叫notify
it receives a parameter called item
它接收一个参数是item
item is an reference to a generic type T
它的类型是一个泛型的引用
this generic type has a constraint that it must implement the Summary trait
这个泛型有一个约束是
它必须要满足Summary这样的一个trait
The implementation here is very simple
里面的实现很简单
we just print out the result of the summarize function
我们只是打印summarize方法的结果
You can see that we're using a colon to identify the constraint
可以看到
这里我们是通过冒号Summary来
You can see that we're using a colon to identify the constraint
进行接口的约束
which is usually called trait bound
也就是trait bound
When the constraints are simple
当我们的约束比较简单的时候
we can use the form of "impl Summary" to do so
我们可以去使用
impl Summary这样的形式
If the trait bound is complex
如果接口比较复杂
or it has multiple generic parameters
或者说有多个泛型参数的时候
such form becomes less readable, we'll introduce another way for trait bound later
这种方式就会变得不易读
Now let's write some code together
现在我们来一起写一下代码
First
首先
let's define a trait called Summary
我们定义了Summary这样的一个trait
it has a function called summarize
它有一个方法summarize
and it has no default implementation for summarize function
并且它没有默认的实现
Next we define a strucl called Tweet
接着我们定义结构体
Next let's define a struct called Tweet
以及
and implement the Summary trait for the struct
结构体对Summary接口的实现
The struct name is Tweet
结构体的名字是Tweet
which is what we just saw
就是我们刚才看到的
Let's define the function notify
我们再定义函数notify
it prints out the results of our summarize function
打印summarize的结果
Then we can use notify in the main function
接着我们就可以在
main函数里面进行使用
Then we can use notify in the main function
我们的notify函数
First let's create an instance of Tweet
首先我们定义了一个
Tweet结构体的实例
Its author is kaichao, and the text is "hello world"
它的author是kaichao, 它的text是hello world
then let's call the notify function
那我们调用notify函数
pass in a reference of the tweet that we just created
传入我们tweet的引用
run the program
我们尝试运行
it has printed the output we want
可以看到他现在
已经打印了我们想要的输出结果
Here we can see
这里可以看到
using trait bound has some great advantages
我们使用trait bound的好处是
One is that function can accept generic parameters that we wouldn't bother to decide it now
我们可以接收一个
具有某种功能的泛型参数
One is that function can accept generic parameters that we wouldn't bother to decide it now
而这个参数的话
我们是不用现在去确定
the compiler will decide it for us when needed
编译器会把我们替换
the function can not only accept a Tweet struct type, but also other types
我们不仅可以接受一个Tweet类型
也可以接受其他的类型
as long as such types implement the Summary trait
只要他能够实现
满足Summary这样的一个接口就可以了
Another benefit of using trait bound is that
trait bound另外一个好处是
when we have multiple parameters
当我们有多个参数时
trait bound guarantees that parameters can be the same type
使用trait bound 可以保证
参数类型是一致的
For example, here the notify function takes two parameters
比如这里我们notify函数有两个参数
one is item1, the other is item2
一个是item1
一个是item2
Each of the parameters is a reference to generic type T
那这两个参数类型是泛型T的引用
generic type T must satisfy the constraint identified by Summary trait
泛型T要满足Summary这样一个约束
You can see that item1 and item2 have the same data type
可以看到item1和item2
两个数据类型是一致的
During compiling, the generic type will be replaced by the final concrete data type
在编译器编译完成之后最终
会被替换为最终的一个数据类型
Use "+" between each constraint When a generic type has multiple constraints
当某个泛型参数有多个类型约束时
可以使用加号
For example
比如这里我们的
here generic type T has two constraints, one is the trait Summary
泛型T除了有Summary接口的一个约束
the other is the trait Display
还有Display接口的一个约束
Display is a build-in trait defined in Rust standard library
Display是Rust内置的一个trait
it's used to format the user-facing output
可以用来实现打印的功能
Next, let's take a look at the use of the where keyword
接着我们来看一下where关键字的使用
Here we have defined a function called some_function
这里我们定义了一个函数叫some_function
it has two parameters, one is t and the other is u
它有两个参数一个是t 一个是u
param t is a reference to the generic type T, param u is a reference to the generic type U
类型分别是泛型T的引用
和泛型U的引用
We can tell that the generic type T has two constraints
那可以看到泛型T有
两个trait的约束
generic type U also has two constraints
泛型U也有两个
The signature of our function is really long and hard to read
函数签名比较长 可读性比较低
Now let's use the where keyword to refactor our code
接着我们用where关键字进行改造
some_function still has two parameters t and u
我们定义的some_function
这样为函数也是有两个参数t和u
and generic type T and U
对应的泛型T和泛型U的约束
here we use the keyword "where" at the end of the function signature
在函数签名之后
我们通过在where关键字
followed by the corresponding constraints of T and U
后面加上对应的
T和U的泛型约束
and separate multiple generic parameters by comma
并且通过逗号分隔多个泛型参数
Next let's see the usage of lifetime
现在我们来看一下
Rust里面的生命周期
In rust, every variable has a lifetime
在Rust里每个变量都有生命周期
lifetime is used to identify the validity or scope of a variable
生命周期指的是该变量的有效范围
或者说是它的作用域
lifetime is used to identify the validity or scope of a variable
那生命周期的英文是lifetime
The advantage of using lifetime is that it ensures the references are valid and prevents null pointers
生命周期的好处是它确保了引用的有效性
来防止我们代码里面出现空指针
Let's look at a code snippet
这里我们看一个代码片段
It defines a variable r
我们定义了一个变量r
then we use curly braces to create a new scope
接着我们用大括号生成了一个新的作用域
Inside the braces we define a variable x
在大括号里面我们定义了一个变量x
the value is 5
它的值是5
then the reference of x is assigned to our variable r defined in the outer scope
我们将对应x的引用赋值给外层的变量r
when x goes out of scope
然后退出我们当前x作用域
let's try to print the value referenced by r
尝试打印r引用的值
we will get a compilation error at current stage
这个时候会报编译异常
The reason is that the scope of r is the outer curly braces
原因是我们的
r的作用域是在最外层的这个大括号
and the scope of x is the inner curly braces
而x的作用域是在内层的大括号
The compiler checks the validity of references at compile time
编译器在编译时会检查引用的有效性
it detected that r try to reference a value whose scope is smaller than its own scope
他检测到
r尝试引用
it detected that r try to reference a value whose scope is smaller than its own scope
一个比自己更小的一个作用域
and raise the above compiling error
那就会抛出相应的异常
Now let's look at the lifetime of references
现在我们来看一下引用的生命周期
most of the time lifetime is implicit
在大多数时候生命周期都是隐含的
which means it can be inferred by the compiler
可以被编译器所推断
just like the type of a variable, we don't need to specify it explicitly
就像类型一样
多数时候我们不需要去显示的指定类型
the compiler can infer the type from the context
编辑器也可以推断出来
but infer will be failed if multiple candidate types exist,
但是当有多种类型都有可能时
in such cases, we must explicitly specify the type of our variable
就需要显示的指定我们变量的类型了
Similarly
类似的
when lifetime could have different scopes
当生命周期可能有不同的范围时
we have to specify the lifetime of a vairable explicitly
我们就必须显示的
指定变量的生命周期
Rust uses generic types to specify the relationship between lifetimes
在Rust里
可以使用泛型参数来指定这种
Rust uses generic types to specify the relationship between lifetimes
生命周期之间的关系
it ensures the validity of the reference
来确保引用的有效性
Here let's look at an example
这里我们来看一个例子
we define a function called longest
我们定义了一个longest函数
it has two parameters which are x and y
它有两个参数分别是x y
both of the parameters are string slice
类型都是string slice
the return value is also a string slice
返回值也是一个string slice
the logic is pretty simple
它的逻辑很简单
get the longer string in x, y and return it
返回x y里面更长的那一个字符串
At this moment
这个时候
there is no way for our compiler to infer the lifetime of the returned reference
我们编译器是没有办法推断出
返回值对应的一个引用的生命周期
we need to specify the lifetime explicitly
我们只能显示的指定
By convention
约定俗成的
we can use a lowercase letter and a ' in front as special generic type to identify the lifetime
我们使用小写字母
前面加一个'
we can use a lowercase letter and a ' in front as special generic type to identify the lifetime
来表示
我们的生命周期对应的泛型参数
Here we have 'a as the generic type
这里我们定了一个'a
这样一个泛型参数
and put 'a to the parameters x and y
并且把'a
对应的给到参数x和y
it indicates that x and y have the same lifetime in the context of our function
表明x和y有相同的生命周期
Similarly, we can also add 'a to the return value
同样的我们返回值也加一个'a的约束
it indicates that the lifetime of our return value is as same as x and y
表示我们返回值的生命周期是和x y是一样的
indicates that the lifetime of our return value is as same as x and y
Now our compiler can successfully compile
这样我们的编译器就可以成功的进行编译
Although here we don't know the exact lifetime of x, y
虽然在函数这里我们并不清楚x,y真正的生命周期
actually we don't need to know the exact lifetime
其实也无需知道
just be clear that at compile time
只要明白在实际运行时
'a generic will be replaced with the one has the smaller lifetime among x and y
'a泛型会被替代为x y生命周期较小的那一个就可以了
For the return value of function
对于函数的返回值
the lifetime it referenced should comes from the parameters of function
它的引用的生命周期必须是来自参数
think about it, if it's not from parameter
如果不是来自参数
then it must comes from the function itself
那肯定是来自于函数本身
since the variables defined inside the function will be cleared when function exits
由于函数内的变量在函数之外会被清空
this will lead to null pointer
所以会造成空指针
In such cases, Rust compiler will not even let it go through
而这在Rust从根本上编译就不会通过
Here we have defined a function named longest
这里我们定义了一个函数名称是longest
it has two parameters x and y, the type is string slice
它有两个参数x y 分别是string slice类型
the return value is also a string slice
返回值也是一个string slice
it uses generic type 'a to specify the lifetime of our return value
我们通过一个泛型参数'a 来指定我们返回值的生命周期
here we can see
可以看到
it defines a string in our function
我们函数里面定义了一个字符串
then return the string slice referenced to the string
然后将字符串的string slice引用返回
since the slice is referencing a value inside the function
由于我们引用了一个函数内的值
the compilation will fail
所以我们的编译会失败
Next let's take a look at the default rules of the reference's lifetime
接着我们来看一下
引用类型的生命周期
such rules are configured in the compiler
编译器所配置的一些缺省规则
After use these rules
如果这一系列规则
the lifetime of references can be determined
使用之后可以确定引用的生命周期
then the generics of the lifetime
那我们对应的
生命周期的泛型参数就可以缺省
can be defaulted
The first rule is that the compiler
第一个规则是编译器为每一个
adds a generic to
引用类型的参数
each reference parameter type
添加了生命周期的泛型
For example, here we define a function foo
比如这里我们定义了一个foo函数
it has two reference types
它有两个引用类型
The compiler will automatically add
那编译器会自动给它加上
two lifetime generics
两个生命周期泛型
'a and 'b to different parameters respectively
'a和'b 分别是对应不同的参数
The second rule is
第二规则是
when there is only one lifetime generic
当生命周期泛型只有一个时
the return values of all reference types
那所有引用类型的返回值
will use this generic of this lifetime
都会使用这个生命周期的泛型
For example, here we define a function foo
比如这里我们定了一个函数foo
it has only one parameter x which is an application type
它只有一个参数x是一个引用类型
its lifetime is 'a
那它的生命周期是'a
Then the return value will just use 'a
那返回值会直接使用'a
as its lifetime
这样的一个生命周期
The third rule is
第三个规则是
when there are multiple lieftime generics
生命周期的泛型有多个时
and one of them is
并且其中一个是
self reference or mutable reference
自身的引用或者可变的引用
then the return value of all references
那么所有引用类型的返回值
will use
都会使用
the lifetime of this self-referenced lifetime
这样一个自身引用对应的生命周期
For example, here we define a function foo
比如这里我们定义了一个函数foo
it has two parameters one is self reference
它有两个参数一个是self的引用
The other one is the I32 reference
另外一个是i32引用
Respectively the compiler will add
分别编译器会增加一个
lifetime generics 'a and 'b
生命周期的泛型参数
'a和'b
Then the return value
那我们返回值的话
will use the lifetime of the self reference
会使用self引用的生命周期
that is 'a
也就是'a
Partial fields of the structure
结构体的部分字段
can also be a reference to a value
也可以是某个值的引用
We shall specify
那这个时候我们就要指定
reference lifetime
引用的生命周期
and noted that
并且需要注意的是
the instance of the structure
结构体的实例
is no longer available outside the scope of the value
在该值的作用域之外就不再可用了
For example
比如这里
we define a struct summary
我们定义了一个Summary的结构体
one of its attributes part is a reference to a string slice
它的一个属性part
是一个string slice的引用
So here we have to specify its lifetime is 'a
那么这里我们要指定它的生命周期
是'a
When we define a string "text" in the main function
当我们在main函数里面定了一个
字符串text
and get its
并且获取它的
first sentence, it's a string slice
第一个句子first sentence
它是一个string slice
Then construct a summary struct
然后构造一个summary结构体
assign the value of first sentence to part
把first_sentence赋值给part
After our first sentence exits the scope
当我们的first_sentence退出作用域之后
then our struct summary will no longer be available
那我们的结构体summary也就不再可用
In another situation,
另外一个生命周期里
we will always meet static lifetime
经常会遇到的概念是静态生命周期
Static means
static 他所表示的意思是
it is valid
当前的引用的有效性
throughout the whole execution cycle of the program
是在整个程序的执行周期
That is to say
也就是说
this reference will remain valid until the program exits
该引用会一直有效直到程序退出
string literal,  the string enclosed in double quotes
string literal 也就是用双引号括起来的
are static by default
字符串字面量是static的
it can be identified by 'static
可以通过'static来标识
We need to use the static lifetime carefully
我们需要谨慎的使用static生命周期
When there is a null pointer in the code or
当代码里存在空指针或者
when the lifetime of the reference does not match
引用的生命周期不匹配的时候
the compiler often reports compilation errors
编译器经常会报编译错误
and it will recommended us to use static static lifetime
并且建议我们使用static静态生命周期
But at this time we have to consider
但这个时候我们要考虑一下
do we really want our references
我们是否是真的希望我们的引用
to be valid all the time in the program
在程序的全局是有效的
If not
如果不是的话
we need to fix our null pointer and
我们就需要去修复我们的空指针和
bugs like lifetime mismatch
生命周期不匹配这样的一个bug
instead of using the static lifetime
而不是去使用static生命周期
Today's course content is over here
今天课程内容到这里就结束了
thank you all
谢谢大家